

#### **Shahadat Hussain**

**D.O.B**.: 27-May-1993

**Mobile**: +91 9101809212

**Mobile:** +91-9008179037 (Home)

Nationality: India

**Location**: Bangalore, India

**Address**: Vill- Chandi, P.O-Sikandarpur

**Skype ID**: <a href="mailto:shahadathussainjobs@outlook.com">shahadathussainjobs@outlook.com</a>

Email: shahadathussainjobs@gmail.com

**Indian Passport no**: L2379777

**Date of Issue:** 15/05/2013

**Date of Expiry:** 14/05/2023

Place Of Issue: Patna (INDIA)

GB Nagar Tarwara, Siwan-841434, Bihar, India

# **Professional Summary**

Skilled Manager - Customer Life Cycle with 3 years of experience in Business Development, B2C, B2B Sales, Client Relationship Management, and Up Selling. Fair understanding in increasing sales revenue, developing profitable and productive business relationships, coordinating with decision-makers, building an extensive client base, generating interest, qualifying prospects and closing sales.

# **Skills**

- Sales proposal creation
- Persuasive negotiator
- Revenue and profit maximization
- B2B sales
- Business development
- Sales pipeline management
- Customer satisfaction
- Researched sales leads
- Client development

- Self-motivated
- Highly competitive
- Interpersonal skills
- Energetic and driven
- Enthusiastic about networking
- Highly organized
- Critical and creative thinking
- Analytical problem solver
- Team liaison
- Strong Communicator

### **Work History**

Manager - Customer Life Cycle, April 2017 to Current

NxtGen Datacenter and Cloud Technologies – Bengaluru, KA

- Achieved departmental objective by hitting the quarterly target.
- Achieved individual objective by meeting the weekly target and once over-achieved.
- Revenue generation by selling high-ticket items and up-selling.
- Achieving ambitious customer acquisition.
- Developed new business opportunities by effectively communicating product lines to leading international corporations.
- Uncovered and qualified prospects and sales opportunities in targeted markets using external resources.
- Organize and execute daily/weekly/monthly plans for adding new opportunities and having 3x amount of quota in pipeline.
- Comfortable in engaging clients to solve customer query and generate new business.
- Managing customer centric operations and ensuring customer satisfaction by achieving delivery and service quality norms.
- Researched clients' business issues and goals to offer appropriate solutions.
- Quoted prices, credit terms and other bid specifications.
- Reinvented how team interacts with prospective clients by developing innovative and creative sales pitch.

- Maintained and organized a customer database of over 2000 clients nationwide.
- Planned client relationship cultivating events to promote growth, resulting in an expansion of clientele base by 60%.
- Organized company files and creating support system to decrease workload and increase productivity of account managers.

Sales Executive, Nov 2011 – May 2014

### Fancy Bag Centre – Guwahati, India

- Providing advice regarding the product portfolio
- Delivered the best customer service in alignment with the company standards
- Always strive to improve the customer experience
- Achieved individual and store sales targets
- Used effective selling techniques to maximize the business potential of the stores
- Updated customer information to ensure an efficient use of CRM
- Created appealing and eye-catching visual displays to attract customers
- Acted in alignment to the store's culture, products, image and target market
- Monitored costs and work within budget
- Liaise with suppliers and source elements
- Managed inventory

# **Education**

#### **Academics**

❖ PGDM/MBA- Marketing & HR

New Delhi Institute Of Management, 2015-17

Bachelor Of Commerce

Gauhati Commerce College, 2011-14

Higher Secondary

Gauhati Commerce College, 2009-2011

**SSC** 

Nichols High Schools, 2009

### PROJECTS/TRAINING UNDERTAKEN

Management Trainee (May 2016-July 2016)

Top Rankers Management Consultant

- **❖** Talent Acquisition
- Head Hunting
- Day to Day report management

### **Computer Skills**

- IT Essential
- ❖ MS Office Suite
- \* Red Hat System Admin I & II
- ❖ Diploma in Hardware Technology
- Service Now
- Inbound Marketing Certification